This app works best with JavaScript enabled.

Website

Our Website Builder

Useful tools for your website

* [Warning-proof legal texts
    
    For privacy policy & Co](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/legal-text-generator/)
* [Industry entries
    
    For Google, Facebook & Co.](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/business-listings/)
* [Online booking
    
    Directly via your website](https://www.jimdo.com/website/online-bookings/)
* [Social media integration
    
    Promote on Facebook & Instagram](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/sell-facebook-instagram/)

For your industry

Online Store

Our Online Store Builder

Useful tools for your store

* [Warning-proof legal texts
    
    For general terms and conditions, privacy policy & Co](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/legal-text-generator/)
* [Industry entries
    
    For Google, Facebook & Co](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/business-listings/)
* [Social media integration
    
    Sell on Facebook & Instagram](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/sell-facebook-instagram/)

Business-Tools

A logo for your business

* [Logo Generator
    
    Create your own free logo](https://www.jimdo.com/website/logo-creator/)
* [Logo examples
    
    Get inspired](https://www.jimdo.com/logo-inspiration/)

More useful tools

* [Industry entries
    
    For Google, Facebook & Co](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/business-listings/)
* [Warning-proof legal texts
    
    For privacy policy & Co](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/legal-text-generator/)
* [Social media integration
    
    Sell on Facebook & Instagram](https://www.jimdo.com/addon/sell-facebook-instagram/)

Knowledge Guide

Expertise, tips and inspiration

* [All Topics
    
    Knowledge guide overview](https://www.jimdo.com/blog/)
* [Website Tips
    
    Get the most out of your website](https://www.jimdo.com/blog/website-tips/)
* [Business Knowledge
    
    Everything about your self-employment](https://www.jimdo.com/blog/business-tips/)
* [Success stories
    
    Inspiring stories by real Jimdo customers](https://www.jimdo.com/blog/inspiration/)
* [Jimdo Updates
    
    What's new at Jimdo?](https://www.jimdo.com/blog/news/)

Help

How can we help you?

* [Help center
    
    Find answers to your questions](https://help.jimdo-dolphin.com/hc/en-us)
* [Contact support
    
    Our support team is here for you](https://help.jimdo-dolphin.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000911966-How-do-I-contact-support-)

Jimdo.com Privacy Policy
========================

* * *

We know legal texts can be complicated, so we’ve put together a [summary](https://assets.jimstatic.com/mato-assets/pdfs/jimdo-website-privacy/EN_summary_website_privacy_policy.pdf) of our Platform Privacy Policy for you.

Please note that the summary is just a small part of our Policy. It doesn’t replace the Policy in any way and is not legally binding.

* * *

We, Jimdo GmbH (subsequently referred to as **"Jimdo"** or **"we"**) would like to provide the visitors to our websites (referred to as the **"visitor"** or **"you"**) with information about the purpose, type, and scope of processing of personal data in conjunction with visiting the www.Jimdo.com website, the Jimdo blog website as well as when contacting our Customer Support. We would also like to provide you with all the information you need to assess and safeguard your rights. We process personal data in compliance with the applicable legal data protection requirements, in particular the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG).

* * *

You can find information about how your personal data is processed as a customer of Jimdo in conjunction with your usage of Jimdo's **online services** on the [Jimdo Platform Privacy Policy](https://www.jimdo.com/legal/platform-privacy-information/).

* * *

In **Section A** you can find information about us as the **controller** responsible for processing your personal data.

In **Section B** you can find information about the **processing of your personal data**.

In **Section C** you can find information about the **transfer of data to third countries**.

In **Section D** you can find information about **how long your personal data is stored**.

In **Section E** you can find detailed information about the **use of cookies and similar technology**.

In **Section F** you can find information about **your rights** in connection with the processing of your personal data.

In **Section G** you can find information about the **terminology** used in this Privacy Policy.

In **Section H** you can find information about the **validity of and changes** to this Privacy Policy.

A. Controller Information
-------------------------

### I. Name and contact details of the Controller

Jimdo GmbH  
Stresemannstraße 375  
22761 Hamburg, Germany  
Privacy(at)jimdo.com

### Contact details of the Data Protection Officer

B³ | Informationstechnologie  
Papenbergallee 34  
25548 Kellinghusen, Germany  
_privacy(at)jimdo.com_

B. Information about the processing of personal data
----------------------------------------------------

* * *

Please note that we have only listed some categories of data/terminology here. We have listed the definitions of the categories of data in Section H to make this document easier to read.

* * *

### I. Visiting our website

We process personal data when you visit our website in order to provide you with content, to enable the management of the cookies used on the website, to secure our IT infrastructure, and to analyze errors on our website. Detailed information about this can be found below:

#### Providing content

When you visit our website we temporarily process data on our web server in order to provide you with the content accessed on the website. This includes our website [www.Jimdo.com](http://www.jimdo.com/) plus all subpages.

#### Analyzing errors

We temporarily store data in log files on our web server and analyze them to quickly identify errors which have resulted in a malfunction or system crash, and to improve our website as a result. This storage and analysis of data is carried out in an anonymized format. This means that we store data in a format that does not enable the data subject to be identified. We also process data about the settings on the page where the malfunction occurred.

#### Securing the IT infrastructure

We temporarily store data in log files on our web server and analyze them to secure the IT infrastructure used to provide the website, in particular to guarantee we can determine, rectify, and secure documentation regarding interruptions (such as DDoS attacks).

We use **HTTP data** for the processing described here.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Our legitimate interests are: Providing you with the content you accessed on the website; guaranteeing the stability of and improving our website; guaranteeing the security of the IT infrastructure used to provide the website, in particular determining, rectifying, and securing documentation regarding interruptions (such as DDoS attacks).

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipient as part of this processing: Hosting providers; error recognition and rectification service providers; performance monitoring and log recording service providers; service providers of tools for analyzing log data.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Cookie banners

You are able to manage your cookie settings for this website. When you next access the website we determine whether you have already provided consent, for example, and activate cookies plus the related analysis and tracking tools in accordance with your preferences. Data from strictly necessary cookies will also be temporarily processed on our web server. More detailed information about the content and intended purposes of the cookies used and comparable technologies can be found in our .

We will process data that you provide when managing the cookie settings for this website and data that is assigned to your device when managing the cookie settings. This includes, for example, your consent and, if applicable, your individual selection of cookies to be used on your device.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Our legitimate interest is the management of the cookie permissions you have given for this website.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### Placing an order on the Jimdo.com online shop

You can order various services on our website. We process data for this purpose to take steps prior to entering into a contract and for the performance of contracts that have been concluded on our website. This includes, in particular, receiving your order, processing the payment, providing the services you have ordered, and sending transaction emails to provide you with information about the status of your order.

We process **online shop HTTP data, order data, contact data, payment data, transaction email data, registration data,** and **log-in data.**

Processing is carried out to prepare and implement our contractual obligations (Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR).

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipient as part of this processing: Hosting providers, payment service providers, subscription management service providers, email distribution service providers (of contractually-relevant technical emails).

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Fraud prevention

When you visit our website we collect and store data to prevent fraud in relation to us and our customers. To do so we process data to analyze how to detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other harmful activities on our website. Before we enter into a contract with you we examine whether there are indications of a potential fraud present. We use an automated process to do this.

We process **HTTP data, and if applicable, contact data, payment data, and log-in data** to do so.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Our legitimate interest is the prevention of fraud and any resulting economic losses.

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipient as part of this processing: Fraud prevention services.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### II. Jimdo blog

When you visit our Jimdo blog we temporarily process data on our web server in order to provide you with the content accessed on the Jimdo blog.

To do so we process **HTTP data**.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Our legitimate interest is providing you with the content you have accessed on the Jimdo blog.

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Blog providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### III. Customer Support

When you contact our Customer Support team or we contact you, we will process your personal data to resolve your/our issues. We also process your data after you have contacted us to analyze the quality of our Customer Support team's response. In addition, we offer the possibility of browsing together with a Jimdo employee in the administration area, which is referred to as "co-browsing".

You can contact us at any time with questions by email, via a private message in the administrator area of your customer account, via the Jimdo Creator app, by telephone, on social media platforms (such as Facebook Messenger), via our contact form and via our live chat function.

We store your query in a ticket system in order to process it and to improve and make our service more transparent. Personal information is only used to deal with your query. When a customer query is submitted via the Jimdo Creator app, we automatically collect client-user-agent-data, i.e. browser type, system language, app version, and the device from which you sent the query. This information helps our support team to understand the issue and provide comprehensive support.

In addition, as a visitor to our website, or as a Jimdo user, you have the option of sharing your experiences with customer support with us after your issue has been successfully dealt with. Feedback takes place directly in the ticket dialog and is not mandatory. We only use the feedback internally to improve our customer support. If you no longer wish to receive support feedback requests you can send us an email at any time to specify your wishes (Privacy(at)jimdo.com) and we will then register your opt-out request in our system. We also analyze the queries dealt with by our Customer Support team to improve our customer support.

In order to provide the contact form and the live chat function on our website, information from the contact form session/live chat session is stored in cookies on your device (see our ). The cookies and the information stored in them may be read whilst you use the contact form/the live chat function in order to maintain your session.

We process **query data, communication device data, and communication data.**

The legal basis for processing the data is our legitimate interest in answering your customer queries and improving our support services (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Should the contact be intended to conclude a contract or perform services as part of a contract then our legitimate interest is taking steps prior to entering into a contract or contractual measures (Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR).

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Customer support service providers, providers of customer support analysis software.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Co-browsing

In order to make it easier for you to navigate our website and the administrative areas of your Jimdo websites (CMS) we offer the option of browsing together with a Jimdo employee where we temporarily use your browser window together on a limited basis. When you initiate co-browsing you are stating that you agree to share your browser view with a Jimdo employee. The Jimdo employee only has read permissions. They cannot see other browser content or parts of your monitor display. The employee also has no write or edit permissions. You can end the co-browsing session at any time. The unique session ID is processed. We do not collect or store any data from your browser screen. We save the data about the session once co-browsing has finished to avoid misuse.

To do this, we process **session data**.

The legal basis for processing the data is our legitimate interest in improving our support services and preventing misuse (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR).

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Co-browsing providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### IV. Web analysis technology

We use web analysis technology on our website if you have given your consent or on the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. our interests in analyzing, optimizing, and the economic operation of our online offering in terms of Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). This enables us to collect and evaluate information about your activities on our website. We carry out this web analysis with both our own web analysis tools as well as those from web analysis and optimization service providers.

#### Jimdo's web analysis technology

When you access our website and have been informed accordingly, we collect information about your use of our website using a web analysis tool we developed and store this in a pseudonymous profile. This allows us to improve our website. Jimdo's web analysis tool logs your email address and the user agent, collates these together, and truncates and stores this data using the hash function. A visitor identifier is generated in this way. We also encrypt the visitor identifier using a random value, the salt, which changes every 24 hours. In doing so we ensure that your IP address cannot be restored from the visitor identifiers stored by us and you cannot be personally identified. We do not consolidate this data with other data and it is only stored on our server.

We process **web analysis HTTP data,** and **web analysis data**. The web analysis tool we use generates and stores the web analysis profile. This includes information about the use of our website, in particular, pages accessed, frequency of access, and dwell time spent on the accessed pages, plus the client user agent of your device.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Our legitimate interest is the improvement of our website (presentation, content, etc.).

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Web analysis technology from web analysis service providers and optimization service providers

When you access our website and have given us your consent, we collect information about your use of our website using web analysis tools from web analysis service providers and optimization service providers and store this in a device profile. This allows improving our website and the objectives of our website. A unique ID is allocated to your device which is linked to the device profile in order to assign this information to your device. This data is stored in cookies on your device (see our ) and may be read when you visit our website. During your visit to our website, we may recognize your device on the basis of the ID that was allocated to it. The aim of the analysis is to discover where the users of our website come from, what areas of our website they visit, and how often and how long they view which pages and categories. The IP address is rendered anonymous prior to storage. To document your consent we store a unique ID that is allocated to your device for the duration of your consent.

We process **web analysis HTTP data**, **web analysis device data,** and **web analysis data**.

The web analysis tool we use generates and stores the web analysis profile. This includes information about your use of our website, in particular pages, accessed, frequency of access, and time spent on the accessed pages, plus the unique ID assigned to your device.

The legal basis for processing is the consent you have given with regard to the (Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You may withdraw your consent at any time via our .

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Web analysis service providers and optimization service providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### V. Marketing

We process your personal data for the purposes of sending you a personalized newsletter, recognizing you on another website, tracking the success of our ads (conversion tracking), showing you targeted advertising for our products ((re)targeting), and for surveys.

Detailed information about this can be found below:

#### Personalized newsletter

You can register for our email newsletter on our website. We also send the newsletter to our customers. Our newsletter provides you with information about Jimdo's products, services and promotions, surveys, prize draws, blog articles, and other similar content. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time using the unsubscribe link contained in every newsletter. We process certain data in connection with this when we send and analyze the success of our newsletter.

We may reconstruct individual functionalities (such as using behavioral data) of our newsletter to understand which content in our newsletter is particularly interesting to Jimdo users. We will only use the results of these analyses for the purposes of improving our services and designing our services to better meet your requirements as well as for targeting purposes. The newsletter, therefore, contains a "web beacon", which is a pixel-sized file that is retrieved from our server, or, if applicable, the server of an analysis service provider when the newsletter is opened. Technical information, such as browser and system information, as well as IP address and the time of the retrieval is collected as part of this process. This information is used to improve the technical performance of our services using the technical data, or the target groups and reading behavior based on the access location (which can be determined using the IP address), or the time of access. Statistical data that is also collected includes determining whether the newsletter has been opened when it was opened, how long it was opened for, and which links were clicked on. From a technical perspective, it may be possible to assign this information to individual newsletter recipients. However, it is not our goal to analyze individual users. Rather, these analyses help us to recognize the reading habits of our users and to adapt our content to our users, or to send them different content in accordance with their interests.

You may object to or withdraw your consent to the storage and usage of your data for sending the newsletter at any time with future effect without needing to give reasons, without being penalized in any way, and without paying any cost for this other than the transmission costs for sending the objection/withdrawal. This can be done by clicking the unsubscribe link in the newsletter, which can be found at the end of every newsletter. Alternatively, you can deselect the "Newsletter" box in your customer account.

Your consent to statistical analysis will also be withdrawn at the same time. It is unfortunately not possible to just object to the statistical analysis in our newsletter. The lawfulness of the data processing operations remains unaffected by the withdrawal of your consent. In the event that you withdraw your consent, the personal data used for this data processing will be anonymized or erased. Data that we store for other purposes (such as email addresses for the member area) is not affected by this.

We process **contact data, newsletter form HTTP data, newsletter subscription data, newsletter tracking pixel data, and newsletter profile data.**

The legal basis for sending the newsletter in conjunction with a purchase of Jimdo's goods or services is Art. 13 (2) of EU Directive 2002/58/EC.). It is also possible to send the Jimdo newsletter on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO).

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Newsletter dispatch service providers, newsletter analysis service providers. We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Using conversion tracking

We use conversion tracking technology on our website if you have given your consent. Conversions are certain user activities defined by us on our website. Conversion tracking is a method for us to gauge what happens after you have interacted with our ads in search engines or on other websites. For example, we can see whether you subsequently carried out a certain action on our website.

If you are shown our ads in search engines or on other websites or you interact with our adverts we can gather information from this and store it in a device profile. A unique ID is allocated to your device in order to assign this information to your device. We can then link this with your device profile. This ID can be stored using cookies (see our ). This processing takes place, if applicable, dependent on your consent given to the respective operator of the website.

If you subsequently visit our website we can read the information stored in these cookies. We can recognize your device in this manner using the ID and retrieve the information stored in the device profile about you viewing our ads, as well as storing further data there. This allows us to record information about the use of our website, in particular any conversions that occur. We can thereby see which keywords, ads, groups of ads, and ad campaigns resulted in the desired actions from users. In addition, we can understand what our return on investment (ROI) is and make informed decisions about our advertising costs. We can also automatically optimize our advertising campaigns in line with our business goals.

We process **conversion HTTP data, conversion device data, and conversion profile data.**

The legal basis for processing is your consent (Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You may withdraw your consent at any time via our .

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Conversion tracking providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Remarketing technology

We use remarketing technology on our website if you have given your consent. Remarketing (also called retargeting) means that we can retarget users who have already interacted with our website (with ads in search engines or on other websites that share the same advertising network as us, for example).

When you access our website we collect information about your use of our website and this is stored in a device profile. A unique ID is allocated to your device which is linked to the device profile in order to assign this information to your device. This ID is stored in cookies (see our ) on your device. If you subsequently use search engines or visit other websites that share the same advertising network as us on the same device, your device may be recognized on the basis of the ID that was allocated to it. The stored information about the use of our website can be accessed using this ID, including allocating your device profile to certain advertising segments. The provider of the remarketing tool used by us can target our ads shown to you in this manner. This processing takes place, if applicable, dependent on your consent given to the respective operator of the website.

When you visit search engines or other websites that share the same advertising network as us, the provider of the remarketing tool used by us can store information about the use of the search engine or other information about the ads that you have been shown or interacted with in the device profile in order to enable better personalization. In addition, the enrichment of the profile carried out by the provider of the remarketing tool used by us enables the placement of various adverts to be optimized for us and other companies for whom they place ads (monitoring the frequency of the incorporation of certain ads, for example).

Your ads are personalized and specifically aimed at you by us and the provider of the remarketing tool used by us using your device profile, in particular your usage of our website. We analyze the information stored in your profile and assign your profile to certain advertising segments on this basis.

We process **remarketing HTTP data, remarketing device data, and remarketing profile data.**

The legal basis for processing is your consent (Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You may withdraw your consent at any time via our .

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipient as part of this processing: Remarketing providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

#### Surveys about our services

You have the option to answer surveys about our services on our website (in particular about customer satisfaction). These surveys allow us to improve and optimize our products and services. We may also invite you to take part in such surveys by email (in the newsletter, for example).

We process **survey data, HTTP data, registration data, and log-in data.**

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate interest in improving our services (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). If you no longer wish to receive support feedback requests you can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link contained in every newsletter. We also analyze the queries dealt with by our Customer Support team to improve our customer support.

We transfer your data to the following categories of recipients as part of this processing: Opinion survey providers.

We transfer your personal data to processors in the USA for these purposes. You can find information about the transfer of personal data to third countries in Section C.

Information about the length of time for which the various categories of personal data are stored can be found in Section D.

### Applicant Data

We process data supplied by applicants as part of the application process. This includes the following information: Name, address, telephone and cell numbers, email addresses, and the personal data contained within the application documents. We only process applications if they have been entered into our recruiting system. This is the case where the applicant has applied to us via our Careers website. If the applicant applies to us via another path that we had not specified (such as by email), we will transfer the data into the system. The applicant then receives automatic confirmations of receipt, invitations, and rejections via the system. We process the data purely for the purposes of handling the application. Applicant data is (re)processed in accordance with Art. 88 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in conjunction with section 26 of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and, in the event of a rejection, is automatically erased after 6 months. In the event that the applicant has consented to the further storage of their personal data, we will transfer the data to our pool of applicants. The applicant may contact their contact within the HR department to erase their applicant account and the data held within it earlier than this. The data there is automatically erased after a period of two years. For more information, please go to our [Jimdo Careers page](https://careers.jimdo.com/).

C. Data transmission to third countries
---------------------------------------

Jimdo ensures that your data is processed in the EU or in the European Economic Area. Should this no longer be possible and data needs to be transferred to a third country, Jimdo will ensure, after prior review, that an adequate level of data protection that meets the requirements of the Court of Justice of the European Union and the EU Commission is adhered to in the country the data is transferred to.

In these cases, the data is transferred on the basis of an Adequacy Decision of the European Commission or the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transmission of personal data to third countries in its currently valid version. These can be accessed here: https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32004D0915.

Data transmission to a third country may also take place on the basis of your consent. You will be provided with details of this separately, if applicable.

D. Storage duration of your personal data
-----------------------------------------

We store your personal data for various reasons (such as technical reasons and legal reasons) for different durations. Generally, we only store your data for as long as necessary for the respective purpose or where we are contractually or legally obligated to store the data for a longer period.

We store HTTP data and server log files for a maximum of three (3) months unless there is a security incident (such as a DDoS attack). In the event of a security incident, server log files will be stored until the incident has been rectified and fully investigated.

Co-browsing session data is generally erased no later than 30 days afterwards.

We store and use the data provided to us by Jimdo users to process contracts. After the contract has been implemented in full or the customer account has been erased, the data will be blocked taking fiscal and legal retention periods into consideration and then erased after the expiry of such periods, provided the Jimdo user has not expressly consented to the further use of their data or where we are permitted by law to further use the data, which the user will be informed about separately.

E. Use of cookies and comparable technology
-------------------------------------------

Information about the use of cookies can be found in our . You can change your settings regarding the use of cookies on our website via our .

F. Information about your rights
--------------------------------

As the data subject you have the following rights with regard to the processing of your personal data by Jimdo, in the event of the respective legal requirements:

* Right of access (Art. 15 GDPR)
    
* Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
    
* Right to erasure ("right to be forgotten") (Art. 17 GDPR)
    
* Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)
    
* Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)
    
* Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR)
    
* Right to withdraw consent (Art. 7 (3) GDPR)
    
* Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR)

Please use the information in **Section** **A** to contact us if you wish to exercise your rights.

Information about any particular arrangements which make it easier for you to exercise your rights, in particular exercising your right to data portability and your right to object, can be found in the information about processing personal data in **Section** **B** of this Privacy Policy.

We are obligated to carefully verify your identity when dealing with your requests to exercise your rights. Please note that we reserve the right to request further information or proof of your identity depending on the sensitivity of the data. This is in place to protect your data against access by unauthorized third parties.

We reserve the right to not process inquiries which are received with unreasonable frequency or without corresponding proof of identity. You will be separately informed of this.

Your request and notification will be stored on our system for a period of two (2) years. Any copies of proof of identity that we receive will be immediately destroyed after your identity has been verified. The legal grounds for processing is Art. 6 (1) (c) GDPR.

G. Information about the terminology used in this Privacy Policy
----------------------------------------------------------------

The terminology used in this Privacy Policy has specific meanings defined in the General Data Protection Regulation. We also use other terms which we explain below, along with the most important terminology from the General Data Protection Regulation:

* **"Analysis data"** means data which is generated by the web analysis software on the basis of the information collected referencing the unique visitor ID of the respective visitor contained in the device's data. This includes information about the effectiveness of ads and assigning users to target groups for ads.
    
* "**Query data"** means data that you have shared with us as part of the request. This includes title, first name, surname, postal address (invoice address), telephone number, email address, and the content of your query.
    
* **"Processor"** means a natural or legal person who processes personal data on behalf of the controller (here Jimdo, or you as our customer).
    
* **"Order data"** means information about your orders. This includes information about services you've purchased (description, scope, number, color, price, currency, order number, etc.), the date and time of your order, and the status of your order.
    
* **"Data subject"** means an identified or identifiable natural person to whom personal data can be attributed. In the context of this Privacy Policy this is you.
    
* **"Conversion device data"** means data which has been assigned to your device via conversion tracking when you are shown our ads in search engines or on other websites. This includes a unique (re)identification ID.
    
* **"Conversion HTTP data"** means data that has arisen by design when the conversion tracking tool used on our website is used via Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). This includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.
    
* **"Conversion profile data"** means data that is assigned to a device profile (if applicable, dependent on your consent given to Jimdo as the operator of this website). This includes the unique ID assigned to your device as well as information about our ads that you have been shown in search engines or on other websites or that you have interacted with. This also includes the generation of such data by the conversion tracking tool used on our website and it is additionally noted on your profile when you visit our website. This includes information about the usage of our website, in particular any conversions that occur.
    
* **"Third party account log-in data"** means the log-in data which is transmitted from us to the respective third party service provider. This also includes a unique session ID while you are logged into your account as well as the expiry date of your session.
    
* **"Third party"** means an individual or legal entity, public authority, agency, or body other than the data subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or processor, are authorized to process personal data.
    
* **"Third country"** means a country which is not a Member State of the European Union (**"EU"**) or a signatory to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. (**"EEA"**).
    
* **"Recipient"** means an individual or legal entity, public authority, agency, or other body to which personal data is disclosed, whether it is a third party or not.
    
* **"Device data"** means data that has been assigned to your device via web analysis software. This includes a unique ID to (re)identify returning visitors.
    
* **"Supplemental user account data"** means data that you can add to your user account. This includes alternate delivery addresses and payment methods (such as PayPal email address).
    
* **"Event data"** means data which is collected by the web analysis software referencing the unique visitor ID of the respective visitor contained in the device's data\*\*.\*\* This includes actions that take place on the website which are called "events". For example, this includes making a purchase, registering, adding payment information, commencing the order finalization process, adding items to your cart, adding items to your wish list, carrying out searches, and considering content. This also includes information associated with the actions that are carried out and are referred to as "parameters". This includes, for example, the value of purchases made.
    
* **"HTTP data"** means protocol data that has arisen by design when accessing the website via the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). This includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.
    
* "**Communication data"** means data that you have provided to us when communicating with us. This includes information that you have provided to us on the contact form on our website, by email or to a chat bot, for example. This may primarily include the following data: Name, date of birth, address, telephone number, email address, and the content of your query.
    
* **"Communication device data"** means data that has been assigned to your device when using the respective communication channels. This includes a unique session ID for your communication session as well as the expiry date of your session.
    
* **"Contact data"** means data that you have provided to us when ordering the newsletter or during the order process for the purposes of contacting you regarding the processing of your order. This includes title, first name, surname, postal address (invoice address), telephone number, and email address.
    
* **"Log-in data"** means the data you use when you log in to your account. This includes your email address and password. This also includes a unique session ID while you are logged into your account as well as the expiry date of your session.
    
* **"Newsletter subscription data"** means the data we collect when you register for the newsletter. This includes the following mandatory information: Email address. There is also optional information as follows: Title, surname, first name.
    
* **"Newsletter opt-in data"** is log data collected when registering for and unsubscribing from the newsletter. This includes the date and time you register for the newsletter, the date and time the registration notification is sent under the double opt-in procedure, the date and time that registration is confirmed under the double opt-in procedure, plus the IP address of the device used to send the confirmation, and the date and time of unsubscribing from the newsletter.
    
* **"Newsletter profile data"** means data in user profiles that we use on a pseudonymized basis to analyze usage behavior regarding the newsletter. This includes data about the use of the newsletter, in particular accessing it, frequency of access and the time spent in the newsletters viewed.
    
* **"Newsletter tracking pixel data"** means data that is collected by design when accessing our newsletter by the "tracking pixel" contained in our newsletter via the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). Tracking pixels are small graphics in HTML emails which enable log files to be recorded and analyzed when emails are accessed. This data includes the IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system used, the page accessed, the page accessed before viewing our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of the visit.
    
* **"Newsletter form device data"** means data that has been assigned to your device when using the form on our website to register for and unsubscribe from our newsletter. This includes a unique session ID for your form session as well as the expiry date of your session. This data is stored in cookies on your device (also see our ) and may be read whilst you use the form on our website to register for and unsubscribe from our newsletter.
    
* **"Newsletter form HTTP data"** means data that has arisen by design when accessing the form on our website to register for and unsubscribe from our newsletter via the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). This includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.
    
* "**Opt-in data**" means data that you provide when managing the cookie permissions for this website and data that is assigned to your device when managing the cookie permissions. This includes your consent and, if applicable, your individual selection of the use of cookies on your device.
    
* **"Personal data"** or **"Data"** means all information which can be attributed to an identified or identifiable natural person ("data subject"); a natural person is deemed to be identifiable if they can be directly or indirectly identified, in particular by an identifier, such as a name, identification number, location data, online identifier, or by one or more particular characteristics specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of this natural person.
    
* **"Registration data"** means data that you have provided to us in the registration form on our website so we can first register you for a user account (setting up a user account). This includes the following mandatory information: Email address and password. This also includes the following optional information: Title, surname, and first name.
    
* **"Remarketing device data"** means data which has been assigned to your device via the remarketing tool when you visit our website. This includes a unique (re)identification ID.
    
* **"Remarketing HTTP data"** means data that has arisen by design when the remarketing tool used on our website is used via Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). This includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.
    
* **"Remarketing profile data"** means data that has been generated by the remarketing tool used on our website and stored in a profile related to your device, and also if you use search engines or visit other websites that use the same advertising network. This includes a unique ID assigned to your device, plus information about your use of our website, in particular pages accessed, frequency of access and time spent on the accessed pages. This also includes information about your use of the respective search engine or information about the ads that you were shown there or that you interacted with there. In addition, this includes the results of the evaluation of this information, in particular the assignment of your profile to certain advertising segments.
    
* **"Session data"** means data that we have collected from the co-browsing session. This includes a unique session ID for your contact session as well as the IP address, date, and time of the session, operating system, and browser.
    
* **"Transaction email data"** means data from transaction emails which we send to process/reverse your order (e.g. an email confirming receipt of an order). This includes the content and time of the transaction emails.
    
* **"Controller"** means an individual or legal entity, public authority, agency, or other body that, either alone or jointly with others, decides on the purposes and means of the processing of personal data. In the context of this Privacy Policy this is Jimdo.
    
* **"Processing"** means any operation or set of operations performed in connection with personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction.
    
* **"Publication data"** means information you have provided to us to publish on our website: This includes your product reviews you have provided us with for publication.
    
* **"Cart data"** means data that has arisen from your use of the cart function. This includes information on services you have placed in your cart (such as name of the service, scope, price, and currency). This also includes a unique session ID for the cart session as well as the expiry date of your session. This data is stored in cookies on your device and may be read whilst you use our online shop.
    
* **"Web analysis data"** means data which is generated by the web analysis software and stored in pseudonymized user profiles. This includes information about the use of the website, in particular pages accessed, frequency of access and time spent on the accessed pages referencing the unique visitor ID of the respective visitor, which is contained in the device's data.
    
* **"Web analysis HTTP data"** means data that has arisen by design using the web analysis tool used on our website via the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)). This includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.
    
* **"Payment data"** means data that you have provided to us as part of the order process to pay for the services you have ordered. This includes the payment method you have selected, plus, if applicable, further information necessary for the respective payment method, such as bank account details.
    
* **"Tracking pixel HTTP data"** means data that has arisen via the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (Secure) (HTTP(S)) upon accessing the tracking pixel contained in our website. This data includes your IP address, type, and version of your Internet browser, the operating system you used, the page you accessed, the page you accessed before our website (referrer URL), as well as the date and time of your visit.

H. Validity of and changes to this Privacy Policy
-------------------------------------------------

This Privacy Policy is valid from _January 31 2022_.

Our website is constantly revised and developed due to technical developments and/or on the basis of changes in legislation and/or to regulatory requirements. As a result, we regularly update this Privacy Policy. This especially applies with regard to the methods we use to analyze usage and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising methods and comparable services, in particular those provided by third parties. The information that is current valid will always be found in this Privacy Policy.
